# **Zac Klammer**

\kappa zklamm.github.io 🚨 zklamm@gmail.com 👂 Corpus Christi, TX

## **SUMMARY**

I'm an experienced software engineer comfortable with back end, front end, or managing cloud services (AWS). I recently created Maestro, an open source framework for serverless orchestration. Prior to working in software, I was a mechanical engineer working in the energy industry.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### **Co-founder & Software Engineer,** *Maestro*

Jun 2020 – present

An open source framework for rapidly deploying and iterating on serverless workflows using AWS Step Functions, AWS Lambda, and AWS IAM

- Built easy-to-use CLI that abstracts away complex deployment logic, downloadable as an NPM package
- Optimized speed of workflow deployment and teardown by leveraging AWS SDKs and designing Maestro to execute commands asynchronously
- Created common templates for AWS Step Functions with the declarative, JSON-based Amazon States Language
- Wrote custom retry/backoff logic to ensure Lambda functions and state machines were created with proper roles
- Co-authored technical case study that explores the area of serverless orchestration, existing solutions in the problem space, and the process of creating Maestro -- maestro-framework.github.io 🗅
- Collaborated daily with a 100% remote team

# **Software Engineer,** *Baytek International*

Jan 2019 - Feb 2020

- Built Microsoft Word plug-in for creating product analysis templates using Visual Studio Tools for Office
- Restructured user roles of company's core software offering to provide more granular permissions
- Assisted with integration of third party gas chromatograph software

# Full Stack Web Developer, Self-Employed

Aug 2017 – present

Built several open source projects using technologies such as React, Redux, Rails, PostgreSQL, HTML, and CSS

- Reaction: A Trello-like application built with a React and Redux front end and Ruby on Rails back end
- Postit: A Reddit-like application built with Rails and PostgreSQL deployed to Heroku
- Airline Routes: An application that allows users to view and filter airline routes on a clickable SVG map

### **Project Manager & Mechanical Engineer,** Southcross Energy

Mar 2014 - Aug 2017

• Managed multi-million dollar projects from initiation to completion

### **TECHNOLOGIES**

# Back End

- Node.js
- RubyRails
- nuns
- Sinatra
- C#SOL

### **Front End**

- JavaScript (ES5 & ES6+)
- React/Redux
- iOuerv
- Handlebars.js
- HTML/CSS

### Cloud

- AWS Step Functions
- AWS Lambda
- AWS IAM
- Heroku

### Other

- HTTP
- REST
- OOP
- Git/GitHub

### **EDUCATION**

### **Software Engineering,** *Launch School* □

2017 – 2020 | Remote

An online school that teaches software fundamentals with a Mastery-Based Learning pedagogy launchschool.com/employers

**Bachelor of Science - Mechanical Engineering,** *Texas A&M University* 

2008 - 2013 | College Station, TX

### **ORGANIZATIONS**

### **Agape Ranch,** Respite Care Provider

2018 – present